ADEELA ARIF

CHEMISTRY TEACHER

CONTACT

03004031312

Kot Ishaq Alam Chock Gujranwala

SKILLS

Communication Skill Administrative Duties

Highly Motivated

Time Management

MS Office

Classroom Management

EDUCATION

MSc. Chemistry

Government Islamia College Gujranwala

2013-2015 1st Division

BSc. Chemistry

National Science Collage

2011-2013 2nd Division

FSc. Pre Medical

National Science College

2008-2010 1st Division

Metric Science

Creasent Publich High School

2006-2008 1st Division

LANGUAGES

Urdu



English

PROFILE

6+ years of experience as a Chemistry Teacher. An organized professional with proven teaching, guidance, and counseling skills. Possess a strong track record in improving test scores and teaching effectively. Have the ability to communicate complex information in a simple and entertaining manner Ability to create a classroom culture that is interactive, student-focused, and effectively managed towards learning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

As Chemistry Teacher

Creasent Public High School

2016-2022

- Maintain a safe supportive classroom learning environment where students.
- Assisting students in doing experiments in labs and taking safety precautions.
- Evaluating and grading class work, practical and assignment of students.
- Assess and look after students progress throughout the term and work closely with other staff to efficiently plan and coordinate work.
- Provide informative presentations to students regarding different areas of studies and ensure that all students.
- Plan the content to be covered in the class according to the curriculum.
- Communicate with parents and colleagues to meet teaching goals and ethical standards.
- Trained new chemistry teachers, emphasizing the importance of classroom control, time management, course planning, and adherence to the curriculum.
- Create a classroom environment that is conducive to learning and appropriate to the maturity and interests of students.
- Create a classroom environment that is conducive to learning and appropriate to the maturity and interests of students.

Home Academy

2017-Present

I have been tutoring Science Books for the last six years to students studying in 11 and 12 and students of Grade 9 and 10. I started tutoring when I was completed my MSc Chemistry degree from University.

- Initiated, planned, and implemented specific learning guidelines.
- Prepared students for standardized tests; evaluated their progress and maintained accurate records of the same.
- Evaluated student performance and providing discipline and guidance.
- · Recognize the different learning styles and student preferences.
- Provide subject-specific content to help students through drop-in assistance.